Hi, I'm Jonas
Do you know what open source is?
Well, let me explain it for you
Basically, it means that the recipe, of any given work
is shared and free for anybody to use
Let me take you back where it all started
In the 1880's
A guy named Richard Stallmann had a problem with the software in his printer
He could fix the printer himself
But unfortunately, he was not allowed to get inside "the black box" by the manufacturer
This frustration was the beginning of the Free and Open Source movements
The essential benefits of Open Source are:
Access to the source, or recipe, of any given work
Free remix and redistribution of any given work
An end to predatory vendor lock-in
And a higher degree of cooperation
Open Source is originally a software related term
- but let's take a nontechnical example of where
the open source mindset is actually used today
Here's Dave
He is a really passionate skateboarder
He loves the community because everyone share tips and tricks, openly
This means that everybody has access to the source of becoming a better skateboarder
Dave has the opportunity of remixing an existing trick and making it even better
He becomes more skilled, faster
If Dave's skateboard breaks
he doesn't necessarily have to go back to the vendor to get it fixed
He can also fix it himself with the help of one of his friends from the community
This is because the design of the skateboard is Open Source
In the skateboard community you share new ideas and remix each others tricks
You cooperate and reach much higher standards than any skateboarder could reach alone
Now, let's take another example
Here's Susan and Michael
They have just bought a new property and now need a new house
John is an Open Source architect
and offers three designs that Susan and Michael can base their dream house on
They choose option A, because it best fits their needs
But Susan wants a conservatory as well
so Michael draws one
and adds that as an extension to their chosen house design
- option A
Susan and Michael choose Company A to help build the house
It should be easy for Company A to build it
because the architectural drawings and guidelines are already produced
- by John the Open Source architect
But during the process
Susan and Michael find out
that Company A's employees are very slow and not very polite
They therefore get Company B to finish the work
It's easy for Company B to take over the project
because everything is openly documented
Fortunately Company B does an amazing job of completing the construction project
In the meantime
Koko and Jun have shared a new solar cell design
as an extension to option A as well
Susan and Michael also decide to add that to their home
Susan and Michael are now happy owners of a beautiful and customized new home
But John is also happy
He can now add two new extensions to his professional portfolio
- without having done anything himself
So now, I have given you a taste of some of the many benefits of Open Source
But before I leave you
I have to put an end to some of the myths that still exist
First
You have no control over your work
That's not true
As the initiator, John - the Open Source architect
verifies extensions and chooses what can be added to his specific project
and therefore also decides where the project is heading
Second
Open = Unsafe
Not true
In an Open Source project
many people are involved
and cooperate to make an even safer product
and to keep unauthorized people out
And third
Everything is free
No
the source itself is free and publicly available
but the house must, for example, still be built, customized, maintained
and provided with water, power and heat
Hopefully, you can now better understand the positive term; Open Source
and the principles within
Please, start opening up
and use the extreme beneficial principles
the way they deserve
As mentioned, my name is Jonas
and I'm representing BIT BLUEPRINT
We have, in collaboration with Moving Monday, made this video
to help scale the positive principles within the Open Source paradigm
We have, of course, made this video free for everyone
to use, modify and share
- so feel free to do that
Thanks for watching!